lybrate.com 2015-04-04

# Overview of the terms of use - Lybrate

Lybrate Inc. ("Lybrate", "Company", "we" or "us") is the owner of [www.lybrate.com](http://www.lybrate.com/) or [www.lybrate.co.in](http://www.lybrate.com/) or [www.lybrate.co](http://www.lybrate.com/) the "Site" or "Sites"). ("Websites" and each, individually a "Website"). Lybrate is committed to your privacy. This online privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") discloses Lybrate's practices for the Websites and subscriber based services ("Services") including the type of information being collected, method of such information collection, use of such information and sharing of such information with third parties. Lybrate can be contacted by mail 199 Sector 15A, Faridabad, Haryana, India - 121007 by phone at +91.901.555.9900 or by e-mail at [hello@lybrate.com](mailto:hello@lybrate.com) for any privacy concerns.  
For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, "personal information" shall mean and include information that relates to a natural person, which, either directly or indirectly, in combination with other information available or likely to be available to Lybrate, is capable of identifying such person.  
Lybrate hereby notifies You of the following: 

(a) What personal information is collected from you through the Website?;  
(b) How the information collected is used;  
(c) How the information collected may be shared and disclosed;  
(d) How Lybrate protects your information; and  
(e) How you can seek to correct any inaccuracies in the information.

**A. What personal information is collected from you through the Websites?**

  1. **Information collection and use.**  
Lybrate is the sole owner of the information collected on the Websites. We will not sell, share, transfer or rent any personal information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this Privacy Policy, the Terms & Conditions and the Terms of Use. Lybrate collects information from you on the "Sign Up" and "Registration" pages ("Profile Pages") of the Websites. Lybrate reserves the rights to collect, disseminate, sell or otherwise disclose non-personal information provided by you. 
  2. **Registration.**  
During the collection of information on the Profile Pages on the Websites, you are required to provide your applicable contact information (such as name, physician license information, e-mail address and the like). A mobile verification code and registration number is used to confirm your identity. An email address is also used to contact you about the materials and information on the Websites. When the Websites request for the confirmation of your identity, the Websites will clearly indicate the purpose of the inquiry before such information is requested. In the case of professional information, professional information provided by you to us will be authenticated against a third party provider. Professional information shall include but not limited to physician license number, details regarding qualifications and specialties and the like. 
  3. **Personal Profile of Doctors and Health Care Providers.**  
Pursuant to registration as a doctor or a health care provider on the Website, you may provide additional information in your personal profile describing your credentials, professional experiences, academic background, biography and the like. Your personal profile shall be available for viewing by other registered participants of Lybrate and will be considered non-confidential and non-proprietary. Providing additional information in your personal profile beyond what is required at registration is entirely optional and can be altered or removed by you at any time. 
  4. **IP Addresses.**  
Every computer connected to the Internet is given a domain name and a set of numbers that serve as that computer's Internet Protocol or IP address. When you browse the Websites, our web servers automatically recognize your domain name and IP address. The domain name and IP address reveal nothing personal about you other than the IP address from which you have accessed the Websites. 
  5. **Third Party Email Addresses.**  
For the purposes of inviting and introducing third parties to Lybrate, You will be given the option to import or otherwise provide email addresses of third parties to Lybrate. On so doing, Lybrate will not store your affiliated username and corresponding password. 
  6. **Privacy of Minors**  
Lybrate strongly encourages parents and guardians to supervise the online activities of their minor children and consider using parental control tools available from online services and software manufacturers to help provide a child-friendly online environment. These tools also can prevent minors from disclosing their name, address, and other personally identifiable information online without parental permission. Please note that although the Websites are not intended for use by minors, Lybrate respects the privacy of minors who may inadvertently use the Internet. 
  7. **Opt Out Procedures.**  
Upon initial communication from Lybrate, you may opt-out of receiving further communication from Lybrate. To be completely removed from the Lybrate mailing list, you may contact[hello@lybrate.com](mailto:hello@lybrate.com). If you are using an e-mail forwarding service or other similar service please make sure to include the correct e-mail address or addresses. 

**B. How the information collected is used**

  1. **Use of Personal Health Information.**  
Lybrate does not collect personal health information about individuals, except when individuals consent to share such personal health information on the Websites to doctors and health care providers. You understand that you may have the option of uploading your health / medical information on the Website in order to enable your doctor or health care provider access your previous medical history. While Lybrate takes utmost care with respect to the security of the information you decide to upload, you understand that any information that you disclose on the Website is at your own risk. By uploading / sharing / disclosing your medical information on the Website, you hereby give your consent to Lybrate to store such health / medical information on Lybrate's servers. Lybrate will retain such medical / health information you upload on the Website for as long as it is needed to fulfill the service you seek to avail on the Website. If you delete your account, Lybrate will delete such medical / health information. But please note: (1) there might be some latency in deleting this information from our servers and back-up storage; and (2) we may retain this information if necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, or enforce our agreements.

Lybrate does not collect or maintain information that would associate this submission with a specific patient or individual. The Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) privacy rule, which took effect on April 14, 2003, allows for the use of de-identified health information so long as identifiers have been "stripped" and a key is not disclosed that would allow the information to be re-identified. Lybrate does not possess a key to re-identify patient data.

  2. **Sale of Assets, Merger, Acquisition, Bankruptcy.**  
Information collected from you may be transferred to a third party as a result of a sale or acquisition, merger or bankruptcy involving Lybrate. 
  3. **Cookies.**  
A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. A cookie cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Use of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on the Websites. Once you close your browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on your browser, you would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on the Websites. You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings of your browser. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or allow your browser to show you when a cookie is being sent. If you reject the cookies on the websites, you may still be able to use the Websites, but it shall be limited to certain minimal functionality. The only drawback to this is that you may be limited only to some areas of the Websites or limited to certain functions of the Websites. Some of our business partners may use cookies on the Websites. Please note that we have no access to or control over these cookies. Lybrate and our business partners may use cookies to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you see on the Websites. 
  4. **Log Files.**  
Lybrate may use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the Site, track your movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. 

**C. How information may be Shared and Disclosed**

  1. **Sharing.**  
Lybrate may share aggregated demographic information with Lybrate's partners. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. Lybrate shall not be liable for the transfer of any personal information resulting from loss or distribution of data, the delineation or corruption of storage media, power failures, natural phenomena, riots, acts of vandalism, sabotage, terrorism or any other event beyond Lybrate's control. 
  2. **Consulting.**  
Lybrate may partner with third parties to provide specific services. When you sign up for these third party services, Lybrate will share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. According to Lybrate's contractual arrangements with parties, these parties are not allowed to use personal information except for the explicit purpose of providing these services. 
  3. **Spam**  
Lybrate maintains a strict "No-Spam" policy, which means that Lybrate does not intend to sell, rent or otherwise give your e-mail address to a third party without your consent. 
  4. **Legal Requests.**  
Lybrate takes your right to privacy very seriously and has taken measures to safeguard and respect your personal information. Lybrate will only disclose your personal information in the event it is required to do so by law, rules, regulations, law enforcement, governmental official, legal authority or similar requirements. 
  5. **Lybrate Forums**  
When you participate in a forum on the Websites including, but not limited to posts, poll votes, and post comments, your name and IP address may be recorded for purposes of maintaining your own account within the Forums, and preventing abuses of the forums. This information is not used to personally identify you outside the Lybrate community. In order to diffuse the information in the Websites' forums to a wider audience, Lybrate may, from time to time, collect some of your postings and group them together to use in a specific publication, print, electronic mailing or other public dissemination. At no point however will your name or IP address be revealed in any publication. In addition, when your postings are used in this fashion, they may be edited to fit with the general content of the publication being prepared. It is important to remember that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information in a forum, through e-mail or elsewhere, that information can be collected and used by others. If your personal information is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your personal information.

You may participate in any forums offered through the Websites, but you agree not to post any material the content of which (i) is defamatory, libelous, obscene, indecent, abusive, threatening to others, or in violation of any law; or (ii) infringes the copyright, trademark right, or other intellectual property right of any third party. You will be solely responsible for all content that you post on any forum available on the Websites. You agree to indemnify Lybrate and its officers and employees from and against all liabilities, judgments, damages, and costs (including attorney's fees) incurred by any of them which arise out of or are related to the content that you post. Forums are intended only for the personal use of Lybrate subscribers, and may not be used for commercial purposes or for organized political activity.

**D. How we Protect your Information**

  1. **Confidentiality and Security.**  
Lybrate takes all necessary precautions to protect your personal information both online and off-line. No administrator at Lybrate will have knowledge of your password. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to log off from the Websites when you are using a shared computer. Lybrate also protects your personal information off-line. Access to your personal information is limited to employees, agents or partners and third parties with whom we are working who Lybrate reasonably believes will need that information to provide services to you. However, Lybrate is not responsible for the confidentiality, security or distribution of your own personal information by our partners and third parties outside the scope of our agreement with such partners and third parties. 
  2. **Links.**  
The Websites may contain links to other third party sites. The third party sites are not necessarily under the control of Lybrate. Please note that Lybrate is not responsible for the privacy practices of such third party sites. Lybrate encourages you to be aware when you leave the Websites and to read the privacy policies of each and every third party site that collects personal information. If you decide to access any of the third-party sites linked to the Websites, you do this entirely at your own risk. Any links to any partner of the Websites is the responsibility of the linking party, and Lybrate shall not be responsible for notification of any change in name or location of any information on the Websites. 

**E. Correcting Inaccuracies**

  1. **Correction/Updating Personal Information.**  
If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire to use the Websites, you can update your profile on the profile pages of the Websites. Lybrate will endeavor to correct, update or remove your personal data provided to Lybrate. 
  2. **Notification of Changes.**  
We may update this Privacy Policy at any time, with or without advance notice to you. In the event there are significant changes in the way we treat your personal information, or in the Privacy Policy, we will display a notice on the Websites or send you an email, so that you may review the changed terms prior to continuing to use the Websites. As always, if you object to any of the changes to our terms, and you no longer wish to use the Websites, you may contact us to deactivate your account. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that Lybrate has about you and your account. Using the services on the Websites or accessing the Websites after a notice of change has been sent to you or published on our Websites shall constitute your consent to the changed terms. 
  3. **Site and Service Updates.**  
As necessary, Lybrate may send you Website and service announcement updates. You will not be able to unsubscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the Websites. Lybrate communicates via e-mail to provide requested services and to resolve issues relating to your account. 
  4. **Consent to This Policy**  
The [Terms & Conditions](https://www.lybrate.com/terms) and [Terms of Use](https://www.lybrate.com/terms) are incorporated herein by reference in its entirety. 

**By using this website, you indicate your consent to the terms of this privacy policy. Lybrate reserves the right, in its sole discretion, to change, modify, add or delete portions of the terms of this privacy policy at any time.**
